あ…。
な…！
（生徒）おい　見ろよ。→
（生徒）じゃ　犯罪者？
（集）行こう。
（生徒）あっ　逃げた。
うわっ！
（亞里沙）
臆測で言うことではなくてよ。
「つなげよう命。
新しい命のために…」
あいつ　ＧＨＱに
捕まったやつじゃね？
（生徒）知ってる。
ヒロミが見たって言ってた。
《葬儀社にいた時間が
やけに長く感じられて→
学校へ行くのが
正直　怖い》
天王洲第一高校の生徒なら
恥を知りなさい！
（集）《久しぶりだ。
学校へ向かうモノレール》→
（生徒）いのりちゃん　気を付けて。
そいつ　犯罪者だよ。
♪♪～
Keep life going.
"Government Bulletin"
For the sake of new lives to come,
- It's been a while since
- don't forget to get vaccinated.
- I took this monorail to school.
- This is a government bulletin.
It feels like I was with Funeral Parlor
so much longer than I was...
And the truth is, going to school scares me.
Hey, look. Isn't that the guy
who got picked up by GHQ?
Oh, I know about him! Hiromi said she saw it all.
So he's a criminal?
Let's go.
Hey, he ran away.
Inori, watch out! That guy's a criminal, you know!
That's not something you say without evidence.
If you're a true Tennozu First
High School student, you ought to be ashamed.
So, everything that makes me whole
Ima kimi ni sasageyou
I'm yours
Nee, kono sekai ni wa takusan no
shiawase ga arun da ne
Itsuka futari nara
Dare ka ga kimi no koto
wo usotsuki to yonde
Kokoro nai kotoba de
kizu tsukeyou to shite mo
Sekai ga kimi no koto wo
shinjiyou to mo sezu ni
Ibara no kanmuri wo kabuseyou to shite mo
Watashi wa kimi dake no mikata ni nareru yo
Sono kodoku itami wo watashi wa shitte iru
So, everything that makes me whole
Ima kimi ni sasageyou
round dance
Shu!
（祭）集！　あ…。
（ざわめき）
Did the people at GHQ treat you nicely?
ＧＨＱの皆さんは優しかった？
（生徒たち）えっ！
ウフッ。
It must have been a nuisance
for you to be interviewed,
（亞里沙）事情聴取なんて
面倒だったでしょうけど→
but we have to cooperate
with the government, don't we?
政府には協力しなくてはね。
は…　はい。
Y-Yes! Apparently a cell phone
I found belonged to GHQ, so...
僕が拾った携帯が
何か　ＧＨＱのものだったとかで。
そう。　無責任な噂を流す人間も
多いと思うけど→
I see.
I'm sure plenty of people
spread irresponsible rumors,
but if you ever need anything, I'll...
困ったときは　この私が　力に…。
（颯太）集！
Shu!
Is that Shu I see before me?!
（颯太）そこに　おわすは
集じゃないか！
How was GHQ?! You got interrogated, right?!
（颯太）どうだった？　ＧＨＱって。
尋問とかされたんだろ？
カツ丼　出た？　あっ　ＧＨＱだからハンバーガーとか？
Did they give you katsudon?!
Wait, at GHQ would it be hamburgers and stuff?
Er, no...
い…　いや…。
Ouma.
（生徒）桜満君　私も　いい？
Can I ask something too?
Is the military really full of gays?
軍隊って
やっぱり　ホモばっかりなの？
はあ？
Huh?!
Were there any scary soldiers?
おっかない兵隊とかいた？
（生徒）エンドレイヴとか見た？
Did you see any Endlaves?
- You're climbing the stairway to adulthood, you jerk!
- Ouma, I didn't know you knew President Kuhouin.
（生徒）大人の階段　上りやがって。
（生徒）会長　握手してください！
Miss President, please shake my hand!
Be quiet, everybody! Calm down!
（花音）みんな静かにして！
落ち着いてよ！
取り越し苦労だったみたいね。
It looks like I was worrying too much.
みたいです。
Yes, it does.
でも…。
うん？
But...
Um... thank you. For looking out for me.
その…　ありがとうございます。
気　使ってくれて。
気にしないで。
No thanks necessary. I only did what
any student council president would.
生徒会長として
当然のことをしたまでよ。
（颯太）生徒会長の
供奉院　亞里沙さん。→
Arisa Kuhouin, student council president.
供奉院グループのお嬢さまで
容姿端麗。　成績優秀。→
She's the heir to the Kuhouin Group,
she's beautiful in face and form,
she gets good grades,
それで　性格もいいんだから
すんごいよなー。
and has a great personality... amazing, huh?
で　こっちが世界史の課題で
このホルダーは防疫のテキスト。
So, here's the World History homework,
and this folder has the Infection Control text.
It's kind of heavy stuff, but...
ちょっと重いけど…。　あっ。
≪（電子音）
ありがとう。　助かるよ　祭。
Thanks. You're a lifesaver, Hare.
あっ！
ううん。　これくらい…。
Nah, it's nothing.
Huh... I forgot we had an Infection Control exam...
そっか。
防疫の試験もあったっけ。
（祭）ねえ　集。
うん？
Hey, Shu.
（祭）何か変わった？
えっ　何が？
Has something changed?
Hmm? What do you mean?
ところでさ…。
あっ！
By the way...
谷尋　どうしたのかな？
What happened to Yahiro?
I heard he hasn't come to school
since the day I got picked up...
僕が連れていかれた日から
ずっと来てないって…。
いのりは何か知ってる？
Do you know anything, Inori?
（いのり）心配？
裏切られたのに。
Are you worried? Even though he betrayed you?
I don't really know.
よく分からない。
≪（ドアの開く音）
≪（春夏）集！　帰ってるの？
Shu! Are you home?
春夏！？
春夏？
Haruka!
"Haruka"?
You... hide!
ちょっ　隠れて！
（春夏）ただい…。　まあ！
I'm ho...
Oh, my!
あっ！
Haruka! You're dressed like that again?!
春夏！？
また　そんな格好で！
Shu, you're not happy to
have your mother back home?
（春夏）あら。　集は　母親が
帰ってきて　うれしくないの？
That's not it...
そういうわけじゃ…。
（春夏）ならば　よし。
Okay, then.
Hello, there! I'm Haruka Ouma.
こんにちは。
私　桜満　春夏。
My name is Inori Yuzuriha.
Shu's been kind enough to let me live here.
楪　いのりです。
ここで暮らさせてもらってます。
うわぁ！　あぁぁ！
It's not what you think!
Er, she has a violent older brother,
これは違うんだ。　その　彼女には
乱暴な　お兄さんがいてさ→
あんまりひどいから
かくまってる。
and he's really awful to her,
so I'm hiding her here!
でも　そいつ　外づらがいいから
誰も疑ってなくて→
But, see, he acts like a saint
in front of other people,
so nobody doubts him... plus he's really tough...
しかも　強くて
ちょっとカッコ良くて…。
...and kind of cool...
何　言ってんだ　僕…。
そうじゃなくて　つまり…。
What am I saying?
No, okay, the thing is...
プハッ！　あー　おなかすいた！
はあ？
Man, am I hungry!
Huh?
（春夏）いのりちゃん
おなかすいてない？→
Inori, are you hungry? What do
you want, Pizza-nya or Pizza Fat?
ピザーニャとピザファット
どっちがいい？→
Hmm, I kind of think I want cake.
あっ。　私　ケーキが食べたいかも。
集　行ってきてくれる？
Shu, would you go pick some up?
今から？
What, now?
Yep. We'll have a tasty dinner
while you tell me the whole story.
おいしいもの食べながら
じっくり聞かせてもらうから。
（綾瀬）いいんですか？　涯。
集を学校に行かせて。
Gai, are you sure it was okay
to let Shu go back to school?
（涯）あいつは　いいデコイになる。
He'll make a good decoy.
Well, Inori is with him, at least.
（アルゴ）
まあ　いのりも付いてるしな。
Gai. The last few fights have us
running short on battle supplies.
（四分儀）涯。　ここ数回の戦闘で
軍需物資が不足してきています。
（アルゴ）ＯＡＵから
金は引っ張れたんだろ？
We got some money out of the OAU, didn't we?
資金はあっても　ルートがない。
購入するにも　運び入れるにもな。
We may have funds,
but we don't have a purchase route,
or a transport route either.
（涯）協力者が必要だな。
We need a partner.
（男性）《締め付けは
厳しくなる一方です》→
Controls on the market are only getting tighter.
《わが供奉院グループの
流通支配率は→
The Kuhouin Group's overall distribution control
前年比　２５ポイント減》→
is down 25 points from last year.
Article 301 of GHQ's special law
taking effect last month is what...
《これは　先月　施行された
ＧＨＱの特別法３０１条の…》
（たたきつける音）
（供奉院）《できない言い訳は
必要ない》→
I don't need excuses for your failure.
《次は　結果を持ってこい》→
Bring me results next time.
《亞里沙。　あしたのパーティーには同行してもらうぞ》
Arisa. You're coming with
me to the party tomorrow.
（亞里沙）《はい　おじいさま》
Yes, Grandfather.
I'll be leaving the back room
jobs in your hands too one day.
（供奉院）《いずれ　裏の仕事も
お前に任せる。　そのつもりでな》
So plan accordingly.
（亞里沙）《分かっています》
I know, Sir.
（亞里沙）分かっています。
私は　供奉院　亞里沙ですから。
I know. Because I'm Arisa Kuhouin.
（春夏）カワイイじゃない
いのりちゃん。→
Inori's cute! A little strange, but...
ちょっと変わった子みたいだけど
何ていうか　ほっとけない感じ？
How to put it... She makes
you feel protective, I guess?
（クラッカーの音）
わっ！
Yeah...
そうだね。
She's a lot stronger than me, but...
あの子　僕より
ずっと強いんだけど→
でも　すっごく
弱く見えるときもあって…。
She seems really weak sometimes, too.
ちょっと！
Hey!
Cut it out, you drunk.
やめてよ！　酔っぱらいは。
Can't a mother cuddle her son?
（春夏）スキンシップ。
いけない？
いけなく…　ないけど…。
I... guess so...
あっ　あった！
There it is!
Thank goodness!
（春夏）よかった！→
With this, I can manage to make
an impression at tomorrow's party!
これで　あしたのパーティー
何とか　カッコつく。
（ダン）カッコつかないだろ？
Gotta strike a good blow
when you take a new post
着任したからには
一発　決めないとさ。→
or you don't make an impression, right?
今日付で俺の部下になったんだからガッツ出してこうぜ！
As of today you guys are my subordinates,
so let's show some guts, okay?
（ローワン）お言葉を返すようですが
イーグルマン大佐。
I don't mean any offense, Colonel Eagleman, but...
ダン！　親しみを込めて
ダンと呼んでくれ。
Dan!
I told you, keep things friendly
and call me "Dan"! Remember?
そう言っただろ？
ミスター　ダン。→
Mr. Dan... these Dragoons
are surface-to-air missiles,
このドラグーンは
地対空ミサイルでして→
洋上の艦艇を撃つようには…。
（ダン）撃てるよ！
and therefore not designed
to fire on a ship at sea...
We can do it!
上に上がるなら
横にだって飛ぶさ。
If they fly upward, they can fly horizontally too!
And what ship might we be targeting?
（嘘界）その標的になる
艦艇というのは？
Awesome question, Scarface!
（ダン）ナイス質問だ　スカーフェース。
（嘘界）嘘界です。
I'm Segai.
ＧＨＱに反抗的な日本人が
船上パーティーをする。→
A Japanese hostile to GHQ is having a party at sea.
He must be planning to make
a deal outside of quarantined waters.
おそらく　防疫指定海域外で
取引をするつもりだろうね。
どこから　そんな情報を？
Where did you obtain that information, Sir?
善意の市民からの通報でね。
A citizen of goodwill reported it.
ほとんどの日本人は
分かってるんだよ。→
You see, most Japanese understand
僕らＧＨＱがいなくちゃ
この国は回らないってこと！
that this country can't get by without us GHQ!
[ﾏｲｸ]（供奉院）わが日本を→
It's been ten years now since GHQ
took over administration of our country.
ＧＨＱが管理するようになってからはや１０年。→
It seems that was rather
too long for us to bide our time.
雌伏には
いささか長過ぎる時だったようだ。
[ﾏｲｸ]（供奉院）われわれ日本人は
顔を上げ→
We, the Japanese people, must raise
our heads and stand on our own two feet.
自分たちの足で
立たなければならない。
緊張しているのか　集。
そりゃそうだよ。
Are you nervous, Shu?
Of course I am! You just called me up
out of the blue with a mission.
いきなり呼び付けられて
ミッションだなんて。
フッ。　いまさら。
かもしれないけど。
A little late for cold feet.
Yeah, maybe... So, what's the mission, anyway?
で　どういうミッションなの？
話したい相手がいる。
There's someone I want to talk to.
But they're not the type to appear
on the public stage very often.
しかし　なかなか　表舞台には
出てこない相手でな。
だから　強引に
押し掛けちゃおうってこと？
So we're forcing ourselves on him at his party?
そういうことだ。
Precisely.
（供奉院）来てくれるとは
思わなかったよ。→
I didn't think you'd do me the honor of coming.
今日のこと　茎道君には？
（春夏）いえ。
Did you tell Keido about today?
No.
それに　私自身にも
責任のあることですから。
And after all, I bear a share
of the responsibility for this.
It was an accident. A tragic accident.
（供奉院）あれは事故だよ。
悲しい事故だ。
春夏！？
Haruka?!
あ…。
She was talking about this party?!
《春夏の言ってたパーティーって
これのことだったのか！》
あっ　すいませ…。
桜満君！？　どうして　こんな所に？
I'm sorry.
Ouma?! What are you doing here?
Crap!
ヤバッ！
待ちなさい！
Stop right there!
Gai! The rest is up to you!
涯！
後は任せた！
Stop right there, Shu Ouma!
（亞里沙）桜満　集！
お待ちなさい！
あなた　いったい
どういうおつもり…。
What are you trying to do, exactly?
Please excuse me.
You reminded me of an old acquaintance.
失礼。
知り合いに似ていたもので。
（亞里沙）お知り合い？
ええ。　キャサリンといって→
Acquaintance?
Yes. Her name was Catherine...
...and she was my pet armadillo when I was young.
昔　飼っていた　アルマジロです。
な…！
（亞里沙）あ…。
She really was just like you,
本当に似ていたんですよ。
自分を守ろうと
必死に体を丸めているところが。
the way she'd curl up into
a tight, little ball to protect herself.
（茎道）すまんな。
ＧＨＱの下働きをさせて。
I feel bad, making you a GHQ errand boy like this.
（嘘界）「いえ。　ルーカサイト計画が頓挫した以上→
Not at all, Sir.
With the Leukocyte Plan frustrated,
アンチボディズが外されるのは
仕方ないでしょう」
it's only natural that the Anti Bodies be dropped.
And Daryl and Rowan?
（茎道）ダリルとローワンは？
（嘘界）「逃げ遅れました」
They didn't run away fast enough.
Right around now they're with
the sportsman, beginning the ball game.
「今ごろ　スポーツマンと一緒に
プレーボールです」
（ダリル）「あぁ～」
（ローワン）水平射撃の準備
完了しました。
We've finished preparations
to fire the missiles sideways, Sir.
Nice! Way to show some guts!
（ダン）よーし　ナイスガッツだ！
やれば　できるじゃないか！
See, I knew you could do it!
You have got to be kidding me.
（ダリル）「冗談じゃないよ…」
（ダン）目標は？
（ローワン）市民からの通報どおり→
Where's our target?
It's en route from Point L-11 to
Point R-22, just like the report said.
ポイントＬ１１からＲ２２にかけて
航行中です。
I'm Ouma, with Sephirah Genomics.
Pleased to meet you.
セフィラゲノミクスの桜満です。
よろしく。
This might be the first time
I've ever seen Haruka at work.
《春夏が働いてるとこ
初めて見たかも》
[TEL]
Shu, get a message to Gai!
Dragoons are targeting that ship!
（鶫）集！　涯に伝えて。
ドラグーンが　その船を狙ってる！
Dragoons?
ドラグーン？
[TEL]（鶫）戦術ミサイル。→
They're tactical missiles.
A commercial ship doesn't stand a chance!
商用船なんか　イチコロの！
《春夏…！》
Haruka!
Get off that thing now!
There's a ferry, so take Gai and...
[TEL]（鶫）早く　その船から逃げて。→
連絡用のボートがあるから
涯と一緒に…。
No!
[TEL]駄目だ！　僕が逃げたら
この船の人たちは　どうなるんだ？
If I run, what happens to the people on this ship?
そんなこと言ったって…。
We can't help that!
じゃあ　集は　どうするの？
What are you going to do, Shu?
僕と涯で　何とかしてみせる。
Gai and I will manage something, just you watch.
I don't recall sending you an invitation...
招待した覚えは　ないな。→
...Gai Tsutsugami of Funeral Parlor.
葬儀社の　恙神　涯君。
次のパーティーには
招待していただけると思いますよ。
I imagine you'll favor me with one next time.
What's that?
それは？
買っていただきたい。
日本の未来を。
Sir, I'd like you to purchase Japan's future.
Gai!
涯！
Excuse me.
失礼。
ＧＨＱのミサイルが
この船を狙ってるって　鶫から。
Tsugumi says GHQ missiles are coming for this ship!
船ごと　やるつもりか。
So they want to take us down ship and all?
命令しろ　涯。
Give me your orders, Gai.
What do we do to save this ship?
この船を救うには
どうしたらいい？
後部甲板で待て。
５分で行く。
Wait on the quarterdeck.
I'll be there in five minutes.
分かった。
Okay.
Okay, let's give this a whirl! Target: R-14!
それじゃあ　いってみよう！
目標　Ｒ１４！→
ドラグーン！
てーっ！
Dragoon... fire!
《助けてみせる！》
I'll save you for sure!
Miss Arisa, please give me the next waltz.
（男性）亞里沙さん
次のワルツは私と。
（男性）いえ　僕と　お願いします。
No, please dance it with me.
（男性）さぁ　お手を。
Here, give me your hand.
Hey! Who the hell are you?
おい！　何だ　君は！
Sorry, but we're doing a rock-n-roll number.
悪いな。
こっちはロックなんでね。
You've got less than a minute before impact!
着弾まで１分切ったよ！
放しなさい！　あなたのような
無礼な男は初めてです。
Let go of me! I've never met
such a rude man before in my life!
光栄です。
あなたの初めてになれて。
I'm honored to be your first.
ふざけないで！　私は…。
目をつぶって。
Don't get smart with me! I...
Close your eyes.
えっ？
I'm about to cast a spell on you.
これから　君に魔法をかける。
本当の君になれる魔法だ。
A spell to let you become your true self.
本当の…？
そう。　本当の君だ。
My true?
Yes. Your true self.
三つ数えたら　目を開けて。
After I count down from three, open your eyes.
Good. Don't move.
そう。　動かないで。
Three. Two. One.
３・２・１→
ゼロ。
Zero.
桜満君！？
Ouma?!
すいません！！
Pardon me!
命中する！
It's dead on target!
うおおああ！！
（ローワン）ドラグーン消失しました…。（ダン）「何だって？」
The Dragoon has... vanished...
What?!
Impossible! Are you sure your
instruments haven't gone haywire?
（ダリル）「そんなバカな。
計器不良じゃないのか？」
We didn't have enough guts!
ガッツが足りなかったんだ。
（ダリル）「はあ？」
Huh?!
All right, then...
Next time we'll fire all of them!
よーし！
それなら　次は→
全弾発射だ！！
しかし…。
But Sir...
さぁ　本気　出していこうぜ！
Okay, men, let's get serious now!
♪♪（『花のワルツ』の演奏）
Fire!
てーっ！
ドラグーン　続けて発射！→
They've launched more Dragoons!
１・２・３…。
そんなに！？
One, two, three... that many?!
Shu!
集！
分かってる！
On it!
ぐあっ！
あっ！
♪♪～
弱い自分をよろう　臆病者の盾。
The coward's shield that
armors the weak self inside.
それが　供奉院　亞里沙
君のヴォイドだ。
That's your Void, Arisa Kuhouin.
♪♪～
（ダン）「おい　おい！
どうして撃たない？」
Hey!
Why aren't you shooting?!
その…。　弾切れです。
Well... we're out of missiles, Sir.
「あっ…」
（供奉院）君たちに
第２次ルーカサイトを→
I concede that your group has a means
防ぐ手だてがあることは
理解した。→
of defending against a second-order Leukocyte.
目の前で見せられれば
信じる気にもなる。
A live demonstration makes
for very convincing evidence.
[TEL]（供奉院）取引は成立だ。
You have a deal.
ありがとうございます。
そのように　涯に伝えます。
Thank you very much. I'll inform Gai.
[TEL]（通話を切る音）
いいニュースだ。→
I have good news.
国内ルートについては→
The Kuhouin Group will be
aiding us with our domestic routes.
供奉院グループが
協力してくれることになった。
やったー！
（綾瀬）シュタイナーが動かせるわ。
- Yay!
- I can operate Steiner!
あぁ…。
でも　どうして　ＧＨＱは→
But I wonder how GHQ
knew about the party at sea...
船上パーティーのことが
分かったんだろう？
A citizen of goodwill reported it.
（四分儀）善意の市民が
通報したからです。
Huh?
えっ？
（四分儀）《善意とは
そう名乗った時点で悪意である》→
That which announces itself
as "goodwill" is always bad will.
《さすがです　涯》
Only you, Gai.
んっ…。
あっ！
えっ？　えっ？
甲板で　いきなり　気絶したんだ。
覚えてないか？
You suddenly fainted on deck. Don't you remember?
いいえ。
とにかく→
No. But I must thank you for carrying me here.
運んでいただいたことには
礼を言います。
寝言　言ってたぞ。
You talked in your sleep, you know.
Eavesdropping? That is not a nice hobby!
盗み聞き？
何て　趣味の悪い。
下手くそなんだよ　君は。
You really suck at this.
何がです？
At what?
I'm perfect in academics,
sports, etiquette... everything!
私は　学業もスポーツも礼儀作法も全て完璧に…。
あっ！
えっ？
甘えるのが下手だ。
You suck at letting people spoil you.
♪♪～
（春夏）いってらっしゃーい！
See you later!
わぁ！　やめろよ　春夏！
そんな格好で。
Haruka, don't come outside dressed that way!
はいはい。
Okay, okay.
まったく　もう…。
For crying out loud...
でも　楽しそう。
えっ？
It looks like fun, though.
集　楽しそう。
You look like you're having fun.
Hey, Inori.
ねえ　いのり。
うん？
僕　初めて　ヴォイドが使えて
よかったかもって思ってる。
For the first time, I think
maybe I'm glad I can use Voids.
Yeah.
そう。
うん。　分かってる。→
Yeah, I know. We have to protect Shu's future.
集の未来は
私たちが守らなくちゃね。
♪♪～
Mou anata kara ai sareru koto mo
Hitsuyou to sareru koto mo nai
Soshite watashi wa kou shite hitori bocchi de
Ano toki anata wa nante itta no?
Todokanai kotoba wa chuu wo mau
Wakatteru no ni kyou mo shite shimau
Kanawanu negaigoto wo
Hanasanaide gyutto te wo nigitte ite
Anata to futari tsuzuku to itte
Tsunaida sono te wa atatakakute yasashikatta